上帝也瘋狂 II
The Gods Must Be Crazy II
字幕合并：柳飄清楓
cleris.diandian.com
這個看似樂園的地方 任何人來此...
Anyone else would die of thirst in a few days. In this arid desert...
都會因干渴而死 因為此地沒有地表水
... that looks like a paradise, there's no surface water.
然而瘦長優雅的卡拉哈里土人...
But the slender, graceful Bushmen of the Kalahari...
卻滿足而自在地生活在其中
... live here contentedly and in complete harmony with their environment.
2萬年來過著與世隔絕的生活...
They have lived undisturbed for 20,000 years because they are...
他們是世界上唯一不需要地表的水 而可以生活的人
... the only people in the world who know how to live without surface water.
當外地那些獵象牙的人來這里...
When ivory poachers in high-tech vehicles intrude into this thirst-land...
都得自己帶著飲水來
... to hunt elephant, they have to drag reservoirs of water with them.
當水喝光時便只好開車 離開卡拉哈里沙漠
And when the water runs low they have to hightail it out of the Kalahari again.
土人在自己的世界中 隔絕地生活與嬉戲...
So the Bushmen work and play in peaceful isolation unaware...
對外界的汲汲與繁忙一無所知...
... of the crowded, hectic world outside their domain...
即使戰爭也只是在 卡拉哈里的邊緣進行
... and even of the wars that are fought on the very fringes of the Kalahari.
有時奇哥談他出外探險...
Sometimes Xixo tells about the time he looked for the end of the Earth...
遇見的一些奇人異事...
... and about the strange, heavy people he met...
但他很難描述外界的人
... but it's difficult to describe those who live outside the Kalahari.
最后只好說外界的人會變魔術...
He always ends by saying the heavy people know some magic...
讓東西跑或飛，但他們不聰明...
... that can make things move and even fly, but they're not bright...
因為缺了那些東西之后 他們便無法生存
... because they can't survive without their magic contrivances.
他們喜歡在早上閱讀新聞
In the mornings, they like to read the news.
他們知道土狼 有了新的女朋友...
They can read that the hyena has a new girlfriend...
印度豹的孩子不見了 而羚羊又開始向西遷移了
... the cheetah has lost a baby, and the oryx is migrating to the west.
大孩子教小孩子如何去解讀 動物及鄰居的閑話...
Older children teach younger ones how to read the gossip about the animals...
卡拉哈里發生的所有事情 都會印在沙上面
... because everything that happens in the Kalahari gets printed in the sand.
全都印在上面了 你委托人的專利權受到侵犯了
It's all printed out here. This is where they started infringing on the patent.
幫我找出來
Give it to me there.
我可以在法庭上提出來 再退回畫面A
Now, that I can present in court. Go back to frame A.
看一下銷售圖
And give me sales.
嗨！安，這是杰夫！...
凱西，你去處理一下？ 拿掉吧
Cathy, will you take this? Take him off.
單位成本并列表
Now, cost per unit. And a printout on that.
杰夫先生說要去香港 處理接收的事
Mr. Geoffrey says he has to go to Hong Kong about the takeover.
- 好的，祝他"旅途愉快" - 他不能參加ECACL的會議
- Tell him, "Have a good flight." - He won't make the ECACI conference.
- 他不能這樣對我 - 他說要你看一下報紙
- He can't do that to me. - He'd like you to read the paper.
說大多數是你研究的 你該得到這份榮幸的
You did the research, so you deserve the honor.
我要在星期三出庭
I have to take this case to court on Wednesday.
- 他說周三前會回來的 - 老天！
- Says you'll be back before Wednesday. - Oh, boy.
當天早上卡比由叢林回來...
That morning, Xabe came with the news that...
說有些動物開始向北遷移
... the animals are moving towards the marula groves in the north.
他對爸爸說："這些野果子 已成熟了，我們去摘吧"
He shouted, "The marulas are ripe. Let's go collect some."
奇沙和奇爾跑過來說： "我們也可以去嗎？"
Xisa and little Xiri ran up and said, "Can we come too?"
奇哥說："我看看你夠不夠大 如果你比我的弓高...
Xixo said, "Let's see if you're big enough. If you're taller than my bow...
土狼就會怕你而遠離你 如果你不夠高，它就會咬你"
... the hyena will be afraid and stay away. If you're shorter, he'll take you."
但奇爾說： "求你也讓我去吧！"
But Xiri said, "Please let me come too."
奇沙說： "我保證一定好好看著他"
And Xisa said, "I promise I'll always stay close to him."
- 今年在哪開會？ - 在艾爾卡卡克拉
- Where is the conference this year? - In Okakarara.
- 是尼布拉斯加嗎？ - 不是，是非洲
- Where's that, Nebraska? - No, Africa.
老天！
Oh, boy.
他們摘了好多野果子回來 回家途中看到...
They gathered a lot of marulas and on the way home they found...
一只受傷的大象足跡
... the spoor of a wounded elephant.
奇哥說："這只大象太衰弱了 它會死掉"
Xixo said, "This elephant is very weak. It's going to die."
他對奇沙說："你和奇爾回家
He said to Xisa, "You and Xiri can go on home.
告訴你媽我找到大象后就回家"
Tell your mother we will come when we've found the sick elephant."
地上有個形狀很奇怪又美麗
There was a very strange and beautiful pattern on the ground.
奇沙看不懂 她一輩子也沒看過這種東西
Xisa couldn't read it. She'd never seen anything like it in her life.
還有一個，跟剛才的一樣美
There was another as beautiful as the first.
她想不出是什么東西會有 這種持續的印子
She wondered how anything could make such a long, unbroken track.
她跟著印子走 看見一個很奇怪的東西
She followed the track and saw a very strange-looking thing.
她說： "那個東西一直在轉...
She said, "This thing went round and round...
所以才 造成了這么長的圖案"
... and that's how it made such a long pattern without footprints."
奇爾看到一顆露珠正在凝聚...
Xiri saw a beautiful dewdrop grow, and when it dropped...
掉了一顆，另一顆又快出現了
... another one began to grow in its place.
他們知道上帝在晚上把 露珠放在樹上
They knew the gods put dewdrops on plants in the night.
但現在卻在白天看到露珠
But here they could see a dewdrop form in broad daylight.
奇沙說： "水一定是這個東西做的"
Xisa said, "I think this thing is making the water."
奇爾這輩子沒看過這么多水
Xiri had never seen so much water in his life.
他不知道世界上居然有這么多水
He didn't know there was so much water in the whole world.
終于找到大象了 他們看到讓大象死的小傷口
They found the elephant and saw the tiny wounds that had made it die.
這些痕跡讓奇哥知道 是外界的人做的...
The tracks told Xixo the heavy people had been there...
卻納悶他們為何把沒用的象牙 拿走卻把珍貴的肉留下任其腐爛
... but wondered why they took the useless tusks and left the meat to rot.
他說："他們真奇怪"
He said, "The heavy people are strange."
波說："我去叫自己家人來吃肉
Bo said, "I'll call Xabo's family to help us eat it.
即使跑一天一夜 也可在明天找到他們"
If I run all day and night I can find them by tomorrow."
奇哥說："我們去叫自己的家人來"
Xixo said, "We'll go call our family."
有好多象牙，上帝需要比人的壽命 還長的時間才能...
There were many tusks. It takes the gods more than a man's lifetime...
讓成象長好，看到這么多 象死掉，讓他們害怕無比
... to make a full-grown elephant, and it horrified them to see so many had died.
奇哥和奇比找到奇沙和奇爾 腳印中斷的地方
Xixo and Xabe found the place where Xisa and Xiri's tracks suddenly stopped.
奇哥說："你看，奇沙和 奇爾爬上去被帶走了"
Xixo said, "Xisa climbed onto the thing. Xiri went up too, and it took them away."
他說："回去告訴家人快去吃死象"
He said, "Tell our family they must start eating the dead elephant.
我去找奇沙和奇爾
I'll fetch Xisa and Xiri."
ECACL會議
抱歉臨時通知 不過，很榮幸有你們光臨
Sorry about the short notice, but we're honored to have you.
謝謝你 我也很想去狩獵之旅
Thank you. I would've liked the safari tour...
- 可是我要準備報告 - 你當真沒事？
...but I have to prepare my presentation. - You'll be all right?
- 沒事，謝謝你 - 好，那就不打擾了
- I'll be fine, thank you. - Good. I'll leave you to it.
- 史帝芬現在在哪兒？ - 我多少有點概念
- You know where Stephen's working? - I think I've got a rough idea.
- 你得去找一番了 - 對
- You may have to search around a bit. - Right.
- 杰克 - 是的
- And Jack? - Yeah?
跟史帝芬說我們會把 其他東西送去給他
Tell Stephen we'll send the rest of the stuff out to him later.
像你這么好的小姐 怎么會來這里的？
What's a nice girl like you doing in a place like this?
- 老天 - 你不吃這套？
- Oh, boy. - You don't buy it.
好，我再試一次
Okay, I'll try again.
- 嗨，想不想陪我去飛行？ - 我為了準備這個才拒絕去狩獵的
- Hi. Like to come fly with me? - I have to work. That's why no safari trip.
這一趟要三小時 我半小時內就可以讓你看完非洲
Trip's three hours. I could show you Africa in half an hour.
我三點半要報告的
I have to present this at 3:30.
研討會主講：安泰勒博士
- 只要半小時？ - 是的，博士
- Only half an hour? - Yes, doctor.
- 你是醫學博士？ - 不是，公司法
- So, what are you, a doctor of medicine? - No, corporate law.
- 好小的飛機啊 - 還有更小的，可惜找不到
- What a tiny plane. - We got a smaller one but can't find it.
- 可以飛嗎？ - 進去吧！
- Can it fly? - In you go.
- 那是什么？ - 水牛啊
- What are those? - Buffalo.
看，手可以放掉，自動在飛 最安全的飛機
Look, no hands. Flies by itself. Safest plane in the world.
- 咖啡 - 早安，老板
- Coffee. - Morning, boss.
- 才開80哩 - 對呀，我睡了一會
- You only done 80 miles. - Yeah, I slept a little bit.
- 你停過 - 我太累了，所以停了一會....
- You stopped. - I was bushed. So I pulled up and...
- 你睡了四個多小時 - 真的累壞了
- You slept more than four hours. - I was real pooped.
- 我早說過快遲到了 - 我真的好累，老板
- I told you we're late. - I was really pooped, boss.
- 過去點 - 沒關系，精神來了
- Move over. - It's okay, boss. I'm fresh now.
哎呀，老板
Jeez, boss.
懶骨頭
Lazy bastard.
- 回去睡吧 - 我現在清醒的很呢
- Get back to sleep. - I'm wide-awake now.
- 睡吧 - 是的，老板
- Sleep. - Yes, boss.
我馬上回來
I'll be right back.
- 嗨！史帝芬 - 嗨！謝謝！
- Hi, Stephen. - Hi. Thanks.
你飛的很好 只是云層會越來越多
You're cutting it fine. There's a hell of a cumulus building up.
萬一被碰上 你就會從2萬英尺摔下來
One of those thermals grabs you, it's gonna whip you right to 20,000 feet.
- 待會見 - 史帝芬，杰克到了沒？完畢
- See you later. - Stephen, is Geoff there yet? Over.
嗨！巴伯，他來了，完畢
Hi, Bob. Yes, he's here. Over.
可以跟他飛回去嗎？
Can you fly back in with him?
我們發現一只重病的長頸鹿 請你提供意見，完畢
We found a sick baby giraffe. We need your advice. Over.
好的，完畢
Okay. Out.
- 你不該帶情人來的 - 她不是情人
- You can't cart your floozies around. - She's not a floozy.
- 嗨！ - 早安！
- Hi. - Morning.
你是在這附近工作嗎？
Do you do some kind of work around here?
史帝芬，快回答，完畢
Hello, Stephen. Come in. Over.
史帝芬，你在嗎？完畢
Stephen, are you there? Over.
- 史帝芬，快回答，完畢 - 巴伯，我是杰克，完畢
- Stephen, come in. Over. - Hi, Bob. This is Jack. Over.
杰克，先別起飛 暴風以快速朝北前進，完畢
Jack, don't take off yet. There's a freak storm moving in very fast. Over.
- 巴伯，他們剛走，完畢 - 他們？還有別人跟他一起？完畢
- Bob, they've just taken off. Over. - They? Someone is with him? Over.
- 是的，完畢 - 是誰？完畢
- Yes. Over. - Who? Over.
- 一位小姐，完畢 - 和你一起的？完畢
- There was this young lady. Over. - Was she with you? Over.
- 差不多，完畢 - 你麻煩大了，完畢
- Sort of. Over. - Boy, you're in trouble. Over.
完畢
Over.
奇哥的朋友瓦卡站在那看 外人留下的印子
Xixo's old friend Waka was looking at the tracks the heavy people made.
奇哥向他問好說自己的孩子 在造成印子的東西上面
Xixo greeted him and said his children were in the thing that made the tracks.
瓦卡也向他問好 說："我陪你去找孩子"
Waka greeted him back and said, "I'll come with you to find your children."
但奇哥說："那兒有只死大象
But Xixo said, "There's a dead elephant back there.
讓你的家人幫我家人去吃象肉吧"
Go with your family to help my family eat it."
高度24987英英尺
高度24991英英尺
高度25000英英尺
停了
They stopped.
- 你座位底下有威士忌 - 我沒事
- There's whiskey under your seat. - I'm okay.
- 拿給我喝 - 你要喝酒？
- Give it to me. - You gonna start drinking?
給我！
Give me.
這玩意喝了酒能飛？
Can this thing fly on Scotch?
喬治
George.
老板？
Boss?
你來接替
Take over.
奇沙說："這東西累了以后就要休息
Xisa said, "When this thing gets tired it will rest.
我們可以跟著印子回家"
Then we can follow the tracks back home."
威士忌沒有了
Running out of Scotch.
這有用嗎？
This any good?
我們在倒飛
We're flying backwards.
我三點半要做報告
I have to read my paper at 3:30.
我怎么回去？ 得找路搭便車
How do I get back? We have to find a road so I can hitch a ride.
朝哪走最接近公路？
So which way to the nearest road?
- 這里是野蠻區 - 我看得出來
- This is baobab country. - It can speak.
- 距離機場至少3百哩 - 老天！
- We're at least 300 miles from base. - Oh, boy.
可能不止
Maybe more.
- 抱歉 - 隨時候教
- I'm sorry. - Any time.
- 我得去打個電話 - 我連在哪兒都不知道
- I have to get to a phone. - I don't even know what country we're in.
嘿！
Hey!
- 什么！ - 他們不怕我
- What? - They're not scared of me.
- 如何？ - 他們不知道人這種東西
- So? - They don't know about people.
- 我們在卡拉哈里內部 - 他們會找到我們嗎？
- We're in the deep Kalahari. - Will they find us?
- 遲早的事 - 究竟要多久？
- Eventually. - How long is eventually?
也許是一天，也許是一星期
Maybe a day, maybe a week.
一星期？我周三要回紐約
I have to be back in New York on Wednesday.
- 你從紐約來？ - 你要我在這過一星期？
- You're from New York? - I have to survive here for a week?
能在紐約活在這就死不了
Anyone who can survive in New York can survive here.
- 我們會餓死 - 這兒有吃不完的食物
- We'll starve to death. - There's enough food around here.
水才是問題 我們只有那些啤酒
Our problem will be water. All we have is that six-pack up there.
他們很渴 但知道那兒有水
They were getting thirsty, but they knew where there was plenty of water.
她說："我太重了拉不上來
She said, "No, I'm too heavy to pull up.
你下來推我好了 然后我再拉你上來"
Come down here so you can push me up. Then I can pull you up."
奇爾一輩子沒下過水...
Xiri had never been in water in his life...
但很快就習慣而喜歡上
... but soon got used to it and quite enjoyed it.
是水嗎？
Is that water?
- 汽油，燃料 - 怎么樣？
- Petrol. Gas. - So?
如果能把飛機弄下來 就可以開了
If I can get this down, we can fly out.
今天？
Today?
我得拆開拿下來再裝配好
I have to take it apart, bring it down, assemble it again.
- 終于！ - 可能明天會好或后天
- Eventually. - Maybe by tomorrow, the next day.
是獅子嗎？
Was that a lion?
- 我聽到了 - 繩子放下，我要上去
- I can hear them. - Let down the rope. I want to get up.
- 它們不會來的 - 你沒關系
- They won't bother us. - You're okay.
- 我在下面呀 - 它們不會過來的
- They're bothering me down here. - They're not coming this way.
萬一呢？
What about eventually?
你不惹它們，它們就不惹你
Don't bother them, they won't bother you.
- 如果它們餓了呢？ - 它們離這里很遠
- And if they're hungry? - They're far from here.
下面全是野獸
It's swarming with wild animals here.
別惹它們就不會有事
Don't bother them, they won't bother you.
我沒惹它們呀
I'm not bothering them.
這一只在垂涎我
This one is drooling at me.
- 是土狼，本來就流口水 - 所以呢？
- It's a hyena. They're always drooling. - So?
別管它，別對它笑 它看見你的牙齒...
Ignore him. Don't smile at him. He sees your teeth...
- 會認為你在威脅它 - 讓我上去
...he might think you're threatening him. - Let me get up.
- 你很享受呀 - 對
- You're enjoying this. - Yeah.
- 為什么你不放輕松也享受一下？ - 享受？
- Why don't you relax and enjoy it too? - Enjoy?
- 這么多野獸，沒食物也沒水 - 也沒房間服務
- Wild animals, no food, no water. - No room service.
對，也沒衛浴 我現在需要衛浴
Yeah, no plumbing. What I need is plumbing. Now.
- 到樹叢后面 - 一個人？獅子在那邊呀
- Go behind that thicket. - Alone? The lions are that way.
- 它們在很遠，如果你不惹- - - 它們就沒事，我知道了
- They're very far. If you don't bother... - They won't bother me. I know, I know.
- 怎么下去啊？ - 怎么上去的？
- How do I get down? - How'd you get up there?
- 獅子吼的 - 不是獅子
- The lion was roaring. - Wasn't a lion.
是土狼在叫
It was a hyena sounding off.
對
Right.
等一下，轉過去
Now, just a minute. Turn your back.
- 拉起來 - 不行，有阻力
- Pull me up. - I can't. Friction.
放我下來
Then let me down.
- 停 - 你要我怎么做？
- Stop. - What do you want me to do?
- 別看我 - 我沒看你，你要我怎么做？
- Don't look at me. - I'm not. What do you want me to do?
放下來
Let me down.
什么好笑的？
What's so funny?
好吧，我不打擾你 你也別打擾我
Okay, I won't bother you, see? So don't you bother me.
- 小心！ - 快走開
- Watch it! - Go away!
快跑，快跑... 爬到樹上
Run, run, run, run, run, run. Get up a tree!
你沒事吧？
You okay?
- 你說只要不惹它們.... - 有小犀牛在呀
- You said if I didn't bother them... - I see there's a baby rhino.
母牛以為你在騷擾它
Maybe the mother thought you were molesting it.
我只跟它說話而已 沒有對它微笑
I only talked to it. I didn't even smile at it.
- 它們會走開 - 你不飛...
- They're going away. - I'm not coming down...
- 我出去之前我不下來 - 上面沒衛浴呀
...before you can fly me out of here. - There's no plumbing up there.
- 你渴了？ - 對！
- You thirsty? - Yes.
- 來，半罐啤酒給你 - 太好了
- Right, you can have half a beer. - Great.
- 先別打開 - 抱歉，噢，老天！
- Don't open it yet. - Sorry. Oh, my goodness.
抱歉，我哪做錯了？
Sorry. What did I do wrong?
是溫的，喝了吧
Well, it's warm. Drink it now.
好，時間不早了
Right. It's getting late.
趁天黑前找食物吧 我看見鴕鳥巢
We have to find food before it gets dark. I saw an ostrich nest.
- 會咬人嗎？ - 不會，它們會踢人，但不太聰明
- Do they bite? - No, they kick. But they aren't bright.
只要躺著，它就看不見了 那只是公的，它在監視蛋
You lie down flat, he can't see you. That's the male. He guards the eggs.
- 如果你引開公鴕鳥.... - 如何引開公鴕鳥？
- But if you can distract him... - How do I distract a male ostrich?
躺下
Lie down flat!
奇哥以為自己看見了孩子的腳印...
Xixo thought he saw his children's footprints...
但其實是一只猩猩的
... but it was only a baboon that had walked past.
- 怎么回事？ - 沒事！蛋拿到了
- So, what went wrong? - Nothing. We got the egg.
這是標準做法？
You mean that was standard procedure?
有火嗎？
Got a match?
又回來了，抱歉
The thing came back. I'm sorry.
- 有火嗎？ - 有打火機
- You got a match? - I got a lighter.
大班呼叫藍吉 大班呼叫藍吉，聽到沒有？
Big Ben calling Ramjee. Big Ben calling Ramjee. Do you read me?
藍吉回答，大班呼叫
Ramjee, come in. Big Ben calling.
- 快回答，藍吉，還是收不到 - 或許還沒到
- Come in, Ramjee. Still out of range. - Maybe they're not there yet.
他說九號會面的 是昨天
He said he'd meet us on the ninth. That's yesterday.
抱歉，老板
Sorry, boss.
...一萬個人要參加開幕典禮 雖然有九架直升機...
- 10,000 people will attend the opening. Although nine helicopters...
還有四架飛機一起搜尋 但沒有馬歇爾和泰勒博士的行蹤
... and four planes are taking part, no sign of Dr. Marshall and Dr. Taylor.
- 是說我們？ - 大概是
- Was that us? - I suppose so.
- 什么博士？ - 動物學
- Doctor of what? - Zoology.
- 你呢？ - 法律學
- You? - Law.
- 我們得小心點 - 土狼？
- We have to watch that guy. - Hyena?
對，它是個懦夫，只要你比它 高大，它就不敢近身
He's a coward. If you're taller than him, he'll keep his distance.
如果你躺下，它就會過來 咬爛你的臉和腿
But if you lie down he'll sneak up and take a chunk out of your leg.
你來當第一班 月亮到那時再叫我...
Take first watch. Call me when the moon gets there...
我就守到那 然后你就可以守到天亮
...I'll take it to there, then you take it to first light.
下來了
Coming down.
- 我好了 - 為了什么？
- I'm ready. - For what?
你只跳25公分 正常的程序呢？
You only jumped 25 centimeters. What happened to standard procedure?
下一次吧！
Maybe next time.
- 我們到哪起飛？ - 3哩外有一塊平地
- Where we gonna take off from? - There's a saltpan three miles from here.
那是幾條街遠？
How many blocks is that?
讓太陽保持在你右肩 離矮樹枝遠一點
Keep the sun over your right shoulder. Stay clear of low branches.
- 什么？ - 那只臭犀牛
- What? - It's that damn rhino.
是公的，不會傷人 干嘛老往樹上爬呢？
It's a male. It's harmless. Why are you always climbing up trees?
我不是動物學博士 我要如何分辨出公母來？
I'm not a doctor of zoology. How do I know about males and females?
差點把機鼻撞壞
Damn near wrecked the nose wheel.
推我一把
Give me slack.
- 你只跳124公分 - 這些東西很危險的
- You only jumped 124 centimeters. - These things are dangerous.
它很小
It's very small.
- 被它咬中絕不放口的 - 滿可愛的
- When it grabs hold it never lets go. - Kind of cute.
不要！
Hey. No!
- 現在輪胎破了 - 這個怎么處理？
- Now we've got a flat. - What do I do with this?
- 為何不丟了它？ - 它還會跑回來的
- Why don't you throw it away? - It'll just come right back.
可以換輪胎嗎？
Can you change the tire?
- 可以幫我脫靴子嗎？ - 為什么？
- Can you undo my boot? - Why?
是踢它的那只 給它的話，它就可以報仇了
It's the one that stepped on him. If I give it to him, he can have his revenge.
- 汽油夠我們回去嗎？ - 足夠起飛的
- Is there enough gas to take us back? - If we get it off the ground.
- 不管用 - 你會修嗎？
- No, it won't work. - Can't you fix it?
沒有唧筒
No pump.
你想當輪子 你瘋了！
You wanna be the wheel. You're crazy.
你看見棍子了？ 我叫開始，你就帶過來
You see that stick? When I shout, bring it this way.
- 我不會開飛機啊 - 我會把你那邊舉高，再恢復平衡
- I can't fly. - It'll lift your side, then center up.
我再叫，你就拉回來
When I shout again, pull back.
拉回來，中間，回頭
Bring it over, center, pull back.
- 然后呢？ - 由我來接手
- Then what? - I'll take over.
我連半自動的都不會開 你想害死我們兩個？
But I can't even drive a manual. Do you wanna kill us both?
你瘋了，我不會開飛機 聽到沒有？
You're nuts. I can't fly. Do you hear me?
- 我不會開飛機呀 - 節流閥
- I can't fly a plane. - Throttles.
- 什么？ - 亮的那個，往前推一下
- What? - Shiny ones, push them forward.
我們出發吧
Here we go.
- 來吧，拉起來，再中間 - 我說過我不會開飛機的
- Come on. Stick it back. Center up. - I told you I can't fly.
就現在，往回拉
Right now, pull back.
- 你說往回拉 - 不是全力
- You said pull back. - Not way back.
- 拉它、拉它、拉它 - 你可不可以拿定主意？
- Pull it, pull it, pull it. - Will you make up your mind?
- 把它放下來、把它放下來 - 什么？
- Bring her down, bring her down. - What?
- 該往那邊開的 - 你說要接手的
- We go that way. - You said you were gonna take over.
- 你該往那邊開的，狗屎！ - 狗屎！
- You should have gone that way. Shit. - Shit.
女人什么都干不成 她終于飛了
Trust a woman to do anything, and she buggers it up.
她越來越會飛了
So she buggered it up.
開 關
低下頭看看"開/關"字樣 關掉就可以滑翔了
Look down and read. It says, "onloff." Switch it off, then glide.
降落傘
我說過不會飛的
I told you I can't fly.
它寫著："降落傘"很清楚
It says, "Ballistic parachute." Clearly.
你看清楚，按下按鈕時 就沒事了
Read it. Press the button. You'll be okay.
我說過連半自動的都不會
I told you I can't even drive a manual.
很簡單，拉起來，放中間 拉回來，就行了
It's easy. Bring it over, center it up, pull back. Get it right!
我示范的很明白，我叫你 "拉過來"不是"拉過來！"
I showed you so nicely. I said, "Bring it over." Not, "Bring it over!"
你會摔斷脖子的
You'll break your neck.
你沒說明清楚 我可能會弄斷我的脖子
You don't explain properly. I could have broken my neck.
我只有一只靴子怎么找你呀？
How am I going to find you with only one boot?
先找靴子吧
Better find my boot.
走開！
Shoo. Go away.
狗屎！
Shit.
等等！
Wait!
嗨，你的單車可以賣我嗎？
Hi. Do you want to sell me your bike?
你看，我給你錢
Look. I'll give you money.
我給你錢，你給我單車
I give you money, you give me the bike.
我要去那邊，那有個人 我付你錢，你帶我過去
I have to go that way. There's a man. I'll pay you, you take me that way.
拿去！
Here.
拜托，我堅持 好吧，到了再給你，坐這？
Please, I insist. Okay. Pay you when we get there. There?
我們試點別的吧？
Well, why don't we try something else?
好的
Yeah, sure.
好
All right.
想的妙！
Good thinking.
你打算咬一輩子？
Are you gonna hang in there forever?
來吧，午餐，嘗嘗看
There. Lunch. Go on, try it.
好，嘗這個
Okay, try that.
我很抱歉，這個拿去
Look, I'm really sorry. Please, take this.
不，拿去吧
No, come on.
再見
Bye.
謝謝，再見 得去找人了
Well, thanks. Bye. Gotta find somebody.
你說你累了
You said you were tired.
回家吧！
Hey, go home.
回你家
Go back to your family.
快走呀，快走！
Go on, get.
快走，走...
Get. Shoo. Go.
英語？
English?
好吧
Okay.
起來！
Get up.
- 走 - 往哪走？
- Move. - Which way?
我的吉普車
To my jeep.
停！你要去哪里？
Stop. Where are you going?
你的吉普車在哪里？
Where is your jeep?
我要去你的吉普車
We go to your jeep.
停！
Stop.
- 前進 - 往哪去？
- March. - Which way?
你知道羅盤后面為何有鏡子嗎？
Know why a compass is a mirror on back?
- 為什么？ - 可以看到誰迷路
- Why? - So you can see who's lost.
好，走西北方向 那邊，前進
Okay. We go northwest. That way. March.
你究竟飛了多遠？
How far did you fly, for Pete's sake?
我怎么找你呀？
How am I going to find you?
該死
Damn.
嘿！
Hey.
嘿！你，走開，別亂動
Hey, you, get away. Leave it alone.
快滾開！
Get out of here.
罐子還我，混蛋
Give me back my can. Scumbag.
你這只土匪
You mugger.
謝謝你
Thank you.
你別過來
You keep away.
別動
Stay there.
看到沒有，你敢過來....
See these? You dare...
別動歪腦筋
Don't even think about it.
你會后悔的
You'll be sorry.
走開！
Go away.
好吧，這是你最后一次喝了
Okay. You can have this one and no more.
別碰罐子，聽見沒？
Leave the can. Do you hear me?
別碰罐子，走開！
Leave my can alone and go away.
別帶朋友來
No, don't bring a friend.
我不會替你這些親朋好友澆水的- -
I'm not gonna water you, your friends and your relatives, and I'm not...
- 日內瓦會議摘要 - 算了吧！
- Excerpts from the Geneva Convention. - Forget it.
上面提到對待戰俘的方法
How a prisoner of war ought to be treated.
"戰犯不得受到非人道的待遇
"No prisoner shall be subjected to inhumane treatment.
- 不得使用暴行" - 停！
- No outrage shall be committed." - Stop.
- 你可以休息3分鐘了 - 你怎么這么急？
- You can rest for three minutes. - What's your hurry?
不關你的事
None of your business.
3分鐘
Three minutes.
我累死了
I'm pooped, man.
別跑啊，回來！我要把你 呈報到日內瓦會議
Don't do that. Come back. I'm going to report you to the Geneva Convention!
回來，你是人犯，回來
Come back. You're my prisoner. Come back!
回到我這兒來，你是我的人犯
Come out of there and be my prisoner!
- 你不能這么做！ - 前進
- You mustn't do that! - March.
如果你聰明，怎么會連 身處在什么國家都不知道？
If you're so smart, how come you don't even know what country you're in?
他們朝哪走了呢？
So which way did they go?
看來只好等他們回來了
I'll just have to wait till they come back.
奇哥看見外人穿怪衣服...
Xixo saw a heavy person dressed in funny clothes...
自言自語 她看來像女人，但是男人聲
... talking to herself. She looked like a woman, but had a man's voice.
嘿
Hey.
這是你問好的方式 我們是這種做法
It's your way of greeting. We do it this way.
抱歉
Sorry.
好吧，照你的方式做
Okay. I'll do it your way.
哈啰，很高興認識你
Hello. I'm very glad to meet you.
他說："你的家人在哪？"
He said, "Where is your family?"
他看了一下印子說 "你一個人怎么來的呢？
He looked at her tracks and said, "How did you get here?
我得找我的孩子 但有兩個外人在那玩游戲
I have to find my children, but two people are playing some game.
剛才聽見他們朝這兒來了
They went that way. I hear them.
- 或許他們會讓你一起玩" - 要我一起去？
- Perhaps they'll let you play." - You want me to go?
他帶她去兩個外人的所在
He showed her the tracks where he met the two heavy men.
說這是他們回頭的地方
He said, "This is where they turned back.
這個人很生氣，因為累的那個人 搶了他的棍子
This one was angry because the tired one grabbed the stick.
然后他得逃跑，真好笑
And then he had to run. It was very funny."
她當然聽不懂了，她也很文盲
She couldn't understand. She was also quite illiterate.
她看不懂符號和印子
She couldn't read the signs and tracks at all.
我們等巴士？
We're waiting for a bus?
真想不到呀
Well, what do you know.
走，滾，我不想看到你 停！
Go away. Bugger off. I don't want to see you. Stop!
你是誰？
Who are you?
奇哥不明白那些瘋子玩什么把戲
Xixo couldn't understand what they were playing.
這玩意會穿透的
This thing penetrates.
你不會傷害女人吧？
You wouldn't shoot a lady.
他說："我得去找孩子"
He said, "I have to find my children."
他記得那些人態度很差 所以也沒說再見
The men had bad manners, so he didn't say goodbye.
我不想涉及你們的爭端 我是美國人
I don't want to be involved. I'm American.
好吧！
Okay.
嘿，不能丟下我不管 你要我死嗎？
Hey, you can't leave me here. You want me to die?
離我遠點
Get away from me.
走開
Get away.
再一次？
Try again, huh?
這不公平，你們不能利用我
It's not fair. You can't both use me.
放開我！放開我！放開我！
Let me go! Let me go. Let me go!
好了，丟掉
Okay, drop it.
- 丟掉 - 丟掉
- Drop it. - Yes, drop it.
- 丟掉 - 丟掉，丟掉，丟掉！
- Now, drop it. - Yes, drop it, drop it, drop it!
可以談判嗎？
Can't we negotiate?
我要回家，如果明天不到比耶 就趕不上回古巴的飛機了
I wanna go home. If I don't get back to Biera, I'll miss my plane to Cuba.
- 不然又要在非洲過6個月 - 我要帶你回基地
- I'll spend another six months here. - I've got to take you to my base!
- 我得趕在周三回紐約 - 坐下來，離那個古巴佬遠點
- I must be in New York on Wednesday. - Sit down. And stay clear of the Cuban.
我要離你們兩個遠點
I'll stay clear of goddamn both of you.
我討厭被人利用當人質
I resent being used as a hostage object.
我得在周三回紐約
Gotta be in New York on Wednesday.
你該留在這 我沒叫你出來的
You should have stayed there. I didn't ask you to come out here.
為了找你，腿都快斷了
I have to walk my arse off to find you.
很好
Well, good.
什么好笑的？
What's so funny?
打開
Switch it on.
大班呼叫藍吉 大班呼叫藍吉
Big Ben calling Ramjee. Big Ben calling Ramjee.
- 你干什么？ - 我干什么？老板
- What are you doing? - What am I doing?
看看太陽，方向走錯了
Look at the sun. You're going the wrong way.
老板，我照羅盤開的呀
Boss, I'm driving on the compass.
這玩意是鋼做的 你卻留在那
This thing is made of steel. You left it there.
看看針
Look at the needle.
你把羅盤弄壞了，笨蛋
You buggered the compass, you stupid bastard.
- 對不起，我沒想到，真的- - - 卡車停下
- Jeez, boss, I wasn't thinking. I'm real... - Stop the bloody truck.
何時放在那的？
So when did you put it there?
我天亮時喝的咖啡
Well, I drank some coffee just at sunrise, boss.
偏離了5小時，40度 你這個笨蛋！
Five hours. Forty degrees off. Stupid bastard.
大班呼叫藍吉，大班呼叫藍吉 聽到沒有？拜托
Big Ben calling Ramjee. Do you read me, for chrissakes?
- 藍吉，快回答 - 大班，你在哪？
- Ramjee, come in. - Big Ben, where the hell are you?
抱歉，這個白癡把羅盤弄壞了
Look, I'm sorry. This idiot bugged the compass.
我等了三天整，你去哪了？
I've been waiting three bloody days! Where the bloody hell are you?
本來我們早就到了 現在偏離方向了
We could have been there, but we're way off course.
我們要花5小時才能走回原路
Now we have to backtrack for at least five hours to find our bearings.
又回原路了，可能在連絡范圍外
We're going back in our tracks, so we'll be out of range again.
等進入范圍再連絡你
I'll contact you when we come back into range.
小奇爾看見土狼足跡
Little Xiri saw hyena tracks.
足跡是剛采的 他知道土狼在附近
The spoor was very fresh so he knew the hyena must be close.
而且是下風，它一定會聞到
And it was downwind, so it was sure to smell him.
他想父親的話...
He remembered his father had said:
"只要你個頭比它大，它就會離開"
"If you're taller than the hyena, it will keep its distance."
土狼不明白這個傢伙 怎么突然變高了
It couldn't understand how this small creature had grown tall so suddenly.
或許土狼希望奇爾再變小 所以就跟著來了
Perhaps the hyena hoped that Xiri would get small again, so it followed...
但保持著適當的距離
... at a respectful distance.
我們的飛機被吹來這...
Well, we got flown here in a kind of a plane...
然后我就找不到馬歇爾博士了
...and then I kind of lost Dr. Marshall.
上吉普車，快！
Get in the jeep. Move.
在那等
Wait there.
- 好，袋子留著 - 為什么？
- Okay, but leave your bag. - Why?
- 你會打人 - 不會，我保證不會
- You swat people. - No, I won't. I promise.
- 我把石頭拿出來 - 你把石頭放在里面？
- Look, I'll take out the rocks. - You got rocks in there?
你開車
You drive.
上車
In there.
發動
Start her up.
往那走
That way.
奇哥看見另一個外人的足跡...
Xixo saw another track made by a heavy person...
由腳印判斷是一個情況不好的人
... and the footprints told of a man who was in a bad way.
他對腳印說：
He spoke to the track:
"我知道你需要幫忙 不過我得先找孩子"
"I can see you need help but I must find my children."
向右轉
Turn right.
停
Stop.
嘿，是我的吉普
Hey, that's my jeep.
我知道，早知道了
I know, I knew it.
- 去吸油 - 汽油？
- Go siphon. - Gas?
但我的油箱是空的
But my tank was almost empty.
要命！
Oh, boy.
嗨！
Hi.
奇哥說："我不知該怎么辦
Xixo said, "I don't know what to do.
你需要有人找水給你 不過我擔心自己的孩子
You need someone to find water for you, but I'm worried about my children.
我走了兩天兩夜 還沒找到呢
I've been running for two days, and I haven't found them.
我想他們可能在很遠"
I think they're very far."
有多少？
What have you got?
大約兩公升
About two liters.
14，15公里
Fourteen, 15 kilometers.
- 里面還有多少？ - 還可跑20公里
- How much have you got in here? - 20 kilometers.
- 你基地多遠？ - 60，65公里
- And how far is your base? - Sixty, 65.
老天
Oh, my God.
- 我的基地才20公里 - 閉嘴！
- My base is only 20 kilometers. - Shut up.
上車
Get up.
小心！
Watch it!
住手！
Stop it!
叫你住手
I said, stop it!
馬上住手
Stop it right now!
小姐，這玩意得小心
Lady, be careful with that thing.
- 給我吧 - 我不要
- Give it to me. - I won't.
我是好人呀 他是臭古巴佬
But I'm the good guy here. He's a bloody Cuban.
給我吧！
Give it to me.
小姐
Jeez, lady.
沒錯，我要發威
Yes, make my day.
好吧，小姐 我基地只有20公里
Okay, se駉rita. My base is only 20 kilometers away.
明天有班機去古巴
There gonna be a plane to Cuba tomorrow.
- 我送你去 - 這小子不知道這是哪兒
- I'll take you there. - This guy doesn't know where he is.
- 你如何找基地？ - 你找的到，你很聰明
- How are you going to find your base? - You can find it. You're so smart.
- 去我的基地 - 誰說的？
- We're going to my base. - Who says?
- 我說的 - 住口！
- I says! - Stop it!
你，給我上車
You, get behind the wheel.
不
No.
不行，退回去 你們得在一起
No, get back. You gotta stay together.
牽他的手
Take his hand.
我叫你牽手
I said hold hands!
好了，過來
Okay, get in.
你繞過那邊
You go around that way.
好的
Okay.
- 現在你們誰能開飛機？ - 我能！
- Now, can either of you fly a plane? - Yeah, I can.
好，開回原來的地方
Good. Drive back to where we started.
小心！老板
Watch it, boss!
糟了，老板，壓死一個小孩
Jeez, boss, we killed a little kid.
- 坐下，我們得離開 - 但老板，他是個小孩子呀！
- Sit down. We've got to get out of here. - But, boss, it was a little kid.
他沒事
He's okay.
- 老板，還有一個 - 王八蛋
- Jeez, there's another one. - Bugger.
奇爾！奇爾！
Xiri! Xiri!
奇沙不知該去哪
Now Xisa didn't know which way to go.
萬一弟弟一個人被留在后面呢？
What if her little brother had been left back there?
停車
Stop here.
土人在這兒找到我的
This is where the Bushman found me.
這表示飛機一定....
That means the plane must be...
這小子掃把星
That guy's only bad news.
- 跟他去 - 汽油不夠了
- Follow him. - We're low on gas.
- 跟他去 - 汽油不夠
- Follow him. - We low on gas.
跟去
Follow him.
嗨！
Hi.
手握起來！
Hold hands.
從那邊下車
Get out that side.
去那邊
Go that way.
停！
Stop.
再見，謝謝
Goodbye, thank you.
怎么了？
What happened?
沒事！只是脫水罷了
It's nothing, just kind of dehydrated.
- W代表水嗎？ - 我不必告訴你
- Does W stand for water? - I don't have to tell you.
嘴張開
Okay, open your mouth.
把我埋在這的人是誰？
Who's the little guy who gave me that stuff?
不知道，他神出鬼沒的
I don't know. He just keeps on appearing and disappearing.
- 他們是誰？ - 是士兵
- Who are they? - They're soldiers.
他們看起來很親密
They look very affectionate.
不對！
No.
- 是你的囚犯？ - 差不多
- Are they your prisoners? - Kind of.
是人質，她搶了我的吉普 又綁架我們
We're hostages. She hijacked my jeep and she kidnapped us.
是你先動武的！你們倆 他有，他也有
You did it to me first! Both of them. He did it and then he did it.
- 她先打我的 - 你打他？
- She hit me first. - You hit him?
- 對 - 她也打我，差點要我命
- Yeah. - She hit me too. Damn near killed me.
你打了他們？
You hit them?
- 用槍劫持他們？ - 對
- Took them prisoner with a gun? - Yeah.
我們還是在走回頭路
No, we're still backtracking.
- 繼續走 - 老板
- Keep going. - Yes, boss.
差點又壓死一個土人
We nearly knocked over another crazy Bushman.
- 你還在蠻荒國度？ - 哪兒來的都不知道
- You still in Bushmen country? - It beats me where they come from.
- 你說不會有人看見你的 - 土人不算
- You said nobody would see you. - Bushmen don't count.
- 老天 - 班，怎么回事？
- Oh, my God. - Ben, what happened?
- 土人爬到車上 - 什么意思？
- Bloody Bushman was crawling all over. - What do you mean?
你干什么？還好吧？ 還好吧？
What are you doing? Hey, you okay? What are you doing?
你干什么？
What are you doing?
在上面干什么？
What were you doing up there?
- 你有沒有看見象牙？ - 不知道，他一定有
- Did he see the ivory? - I don't know. He must have.
- 不能放他走 - 沒錯
- Then you can't let him go. - That's right.
你是監獵員
You a game warden?
抓上來
Get him in here.
你上車跟我們來，上車
You come with us. You get in there.
拿去
Here.
- 老板？ - 逼他上車
- Boss? - Make him get in.
上車跟我們走，你上車
You come with us. You get in there.
你上車！
You get in there!
不能這么做，上車
You mustn't do that. Get in there.
你什么都做不好
Can't you do anything right?
- 老板 - 把他綁起來
- Jeez, boss. - Get me a tie-down.
你打算怎么做，老板？
What are you gonna do, boss?
這么做是非法的又怎樣 是他們先的
So what if it's illegal, they did it to me.
他要走那邊 他要走那邊
He wants to go that way, he wants to go that way.
有槍的人可以決定
The one with the gun gets to say.
我有槍所以決定去飛機那
And I've got the gun, and I say we go to the plane.
好的
Okay.
上吉普
In the jeep.
我們一到飛機那，吉普就還你
When we get there, you can have your jeep back.
- 還有槍 - 再說吧！
- And my gun. - We'll see about that.
- 你這是干什么？ - 是他的東西
- What do you think you're doing? - It's his, boss.
停！
Stop.
印子又出現了
Here are those tracks again.
飛機一定在那邊
The plane must be that way.
- 我不想再當輪子了 - 我們可以修
- I'm not gonna be the wheel again. - Now we can fix it.
- 我沒看到唧筒 - 不要，看好他們
- I don't see a pump. - Don't! You've got to watch them.
- 是你的人？ - 不是
- One of yours? - No.
監獵員
Game rangers.
- 你打算怎么做？ - 別讓他看見象牙
- What are we gonna do? - Don't let him see the ivory.
或許他們有唧筒
Maybe they've got a pump.
你能借我們唧筒嗎？
Could you lend us a pump?
什么？
What?
我們能借唧筒用在...？
Could we borrow a pump with a...?
噢，不要！
Oh, no!
你們對他怎樣了？
What have you done to him?
丟掉！
Drop that!
Throw it away!
喬治
George.
拿槍
Get the gun.
現在怎么辦，老板？
What do we do now, boss?
- 綁起來 - 老板？
- Tie them up. - Boss?
拿過來
Give me that.
- 拿繩子 - 是，老板
- Get the tie-downs. - Yes, boss.
- 怎么回事？ - 我討厭盜獵的
- What's this about? - I don't like game rangers.
- 我不是盜獵的 - 我也不是
- I'm not a game ranger. - Me too.
- 我只是找到這個，老板 - 兩個兩個綁
- This is all I've got, boss. - Tie them two by two.
這下該怎么做？
What are we gonna do now, boss?
我得跟藍吉談談
I gotta talk to Ramjee.
大班呼叫藍吉，聽到沒有？
Big Ben calling Ramjee. Do you read me?
藍吉，聽到沒有？
Ramjee, do you read me?
距離太遠了
Out of range again.
喬治，你看到圓頂了嗎？
George, you see that dome?
我上去連絡
I'm gonna go up there to get range.
去告訴藍吉
Got to talk to Ramjee about this.
交給你了，好好看著他們
I'm leaving you in charge. You watch these people.
你們沒事吧？乖一點 不會傷到你們
Okay, now, you people. You behave, nobody gets hurt.
拿槍！
Get the gun!
嘿，你不能這么做 老板會殺了你
Hey, you mustn't do that. My boss will kill you!
- 拿到了 - 好，走吧
- Got it. - Okay, let's go.
- 上車 - 什么意思？
- Get in. - What do you mean, "Get in"?
快走
Move it.
先生，一起來吧
Mister, come with us.
- 我也要去，他會殺我的 - 你，一檔上路
- I'm gonna come too. He's gonna kill me. - You, give me first gear.
快！
Hurry.
- 我早說沒汽油的 - 我們下車
- I told you we're low on gas. - Let's get out of here.
快走
Move your ass, man.
今天真精彩，盜獵的 士兵和女人
What a day. Game rangers, two soldiers and a woman.
- 你怎么對他們的？ - 把他們綁起來
- What did you do with them? - I tied them up.
怎么回事？
What the hell?
喬治！
George!
是的，老板？
Yes, boss?
該你了！
Your turn!
- 該你了！ - 不，不是！
- Your turn! - No, it's not!
- 是！ - 不，不是！
- It is! - No, it's not!
非逮到這混蛋
I'll get the bastard!
起來幫我松綁
No, get up. Untie me.
快呀
Come on.
嘿！
Hey!
天啊
Oh, man.
等一下 他沒那么瘋
Wait a minute. He's not so crazy.
他知道自己在做什么
He knows what he's doing.
他放火燒出一條生路
He's making a firebreak. Clever little bugger.
會燒完的
It'll burn out now.
燒完了
That's it.
是你的孩子？
They're your kids?
我們剛才碰過面 有一個小的還有另一個
We passed them back there. There's a tiny one and the other one.
對，那邊
That way.
- 你怎么哭了？ - 他的孩子不見了
- Why are you crying? - He lost his kids.
我告訴他在哪
I told him where to find them.
你又要走了
So you have to disappear again.
再見...
Goodbye...
謝謝你
...and thank you.
再見，謝謝你
Goodbye and thank you.
小心！他有槍
Watch it! He's got a gun!
回來呀！
Out of my way!
- 我要你們再做一次 - 做什么？！
- I want you guys to do that again. - Do what?!
- 剛才做的 - 為什么？
- What you just did. - What the hell for?
是遠距離 他打不中移動的目標的
It's a telescopic sight. He can't hit a moving target.
- 不！ - 當我一下令...
- No! - When I say go...
你就拼命跑，好嗎？
...you run around like crazy. All right?
開始！
Go!
別動啊，混蛋
Stand still, you bastards.
丟掉
Throw it away.
好的，好的... 我是你的囚犯
Okay. Okay. Okay. I'm your goddamn prisoner.
我不要你 沒用的人犯
I don't want you. You're a shitty prisoner.
奇爾！
Xiri!
不要一次拉拉雜雜說一堆 告訴我你在哪里就好了
你說什么？
- 好了，謝謝 - 好的，再見
- Okay, thank you. - Okay, goodbye.
一路回古巴，可別迷路了
Bugger off to Cuba and don't get lost.
看到那個山丘了嗎？
See that hill over there?
直走過去，就找到吉普了
You head straight for it, and you'll find your jeep.
再見！
Goodbye.
好，出來
Okay, out.
你開車
You drive the jeep.
- 上哪去？老板 - 去我基地
- Where we going, boss? - To my base.
我們會判多久？
How long will we get?
你可能一年 但這個混蛋可久了
Maybe you'll get a year, but this bastard's gonna sit for a long time.
ECACL會議
There are 12 planes and 9 helicopters searching...
他們一共派出12架飛機 9架直升機...
搜索4百公里范圍
...in a radius of 400 kilometers.
加起來總共是2萬...
So we are covering an area of 20,000...
- 我們現在是不是要接吻呢？ - 是的
- Isn't this where we kiss? - Yes.
拉我上來！上來！
Pull me up! Pull me up!
你撕破我的洋裝了，放我下來
You're tearing my dress! Let me down.
放我下來！
No, pull me up.
算了
Don't bother.
我看不見！
I can't see!
老天！
Oh, boy.
現在會做了吧？
Now can you do it right?